<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R.M. Sandu</title>
    <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://raluca-san.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>R.M. Sandu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2021 Raluca-Maria Sandu. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 14:37:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://raluca-san.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>R.M. Sandu</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volumetric Quantitative Ablation Margins for Assessment of Ablation Completeness in Thermal Ablation of Liver Tumours</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 14:37:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 20:08:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, World!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Volumetric Assessment of CT-guided Ablation  Treatments for Colorectal Liver Metastases</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-quantitative-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-quantitative-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative volumetric assessment of percutaneous image-guided microwave ablations for colorectal liver metastases</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-quantitative-2019-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-quantitative-2019-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereotactic Image-Guidance  for Ablation of Malignant Liver  Tumors</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/paolucci-stereotactic-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/paolucci-stereotactic-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative volumetric assessment of percutaneous image-guided  microwave ablations for colorectal liver metastases</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-quantitative-2019-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/sandu-quantitative-2019-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasound based planning and navigation for non anatomical liver resections — an ex-vivo study</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/paolucci-ultrasound-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/paolucci-ultrasound-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Framework For The Quantitative Assessment of Image-guided Percutaneous Ablation of Hepatic Lesions</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/hrabuska-framework-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/publication/hrabuska-framework-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HiperNav: Marie Skłodowska-Curie PhD Fellowship </title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/hipernav/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:59:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/hipernav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HiPerNav (High Performance Soft Tissue Navigation) is an Innovative Training Network (ITN) funded through a EU Marie Skłodowska-Curie grant. This project has received funding from the European Union’s Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under grant agreement No. 722068. I am one of the 14 funded PhD’s working on the project. My PhD project is carried out in the Image-Guided Therapy group at the ARTORG Center for Biomedical Engineering (University of Bern).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more information about the project on the website of the project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hipernav.eu/&#34;&gt;https://hipernav.eu/&lt;/a&gt;
A video introduction of my PhD project can be found at this link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hipernav.eu/esr-9/&#34;&gt;https://hipernav.eu/esr-9/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAVERRIC - Microwave Ablation Versus Resection for Resectable Colorectal Liver Metastases</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/maverric/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:59:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/maverric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAVERRIC is the clinical project from where I collected and analyzed all of the data related to my PhD project. It provides interventional data from CT-guided microwave ablation interventions for liver tumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt from the clinicaltrials.gov website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims to prove that a strategy of first line local ablation of colorectal liver metastases with microwaves is not inferior to liver resections in terms of survival rates at three years with secondary endpoints being survival at five and ten years, interventional complication rates, length of stay, ablation precision measurements, need for further interventions and health-economic analysis.
A cohort of 100 patients treated with CT guided microwave ablation of 1-5 metastases &amp;lt;31mm in size will be followed and compared with propensity scored matched controls from the Swedish liver surgery registry - Sweliv.
The study is a multi-institutional effort by the Hepato Pancreatico Biliary (HPB) units in Stockholm Sweden, Bern Switzerland and Groningen in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph displayed here shows historical data from the Swedish liver registry with survival after liver resection for colorectal liver metastases, upper 95% CI in green and lower in red.
The blue line are the patients included in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Thesis Project</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/master/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:59:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The topic of MSc Thesis project was pixel-wise automated segmentation of skin surface structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus,  this  study  aims  to  provide semantic description of skin at pixel level by combining information related to skin texture, color and
context.  To  achieve  this  goal,  image  annotation  tools  and  data  analytics  methods  for  semantic
segmentation are implemented and applied. Their purpose is to drive automatic classification of skin
structures at pixel-level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first necessary step was building a tool to manually annotate images to serve as learning material. Thus, I
designed and implemented a web-browser based editor using HTML5, JavaScript and jQuery. The website allows
loading a source image on which several skin structures of interest can be annotated concomitantly. Annotations
made  can  be  exported  offline  into  individual  segmentation  layers  separated  by  the  structure  type.  The
annotation tool is currently used within several projects at Philips Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to build the input feature matrix, I pre-processed the images and extracted features using morphological
operations, contour retrieval methods, contrast enhancement and Gaussian Pyramid. I then applied machine
learning algorithms (Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forests, SVM, k-means, PCA) and evaluated
their classification performance through different metrics. We obtained the best classification performance with
the  Random  Forests  model.  We  observed  that  adding  a  four-level  Gaussian  Pyramid  to  the  feature  space
enhances greatly the classification  performance, from approximately 81% to 96% correctly classified for the
positive class. In this work I used Python programming language with Numpy, OpenCV and Scikit-learn amongst
other libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Thesis Project</title>
      <link>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:59:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://raluca-san.github.io/project/bachelor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my BSc thesis project, I implemented signal processing and feature extraction methods in MATLAB for respiratory capnography (CO2) signals acquired in a clinical research study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capnography  is  a  non-invasive  monitoring  technique  of  the  carbon  dioxide  (CO 2 )
concentration  from  the  exhaled  breath.  It  is  extensively  used  in  clinical  environments  for
mechanically  ventilated  patients  that  undergo  anesthesia.  Capnography  has  the  potential  to
identify hypoventilation  or hyperventilation in emergency care settings,  to aid resuscitation
and  to  monitor  or  diagnose  respiratory  dysfunctions.  In  capnography,  the  expired  carbon
dioxide can be measured as a function of time (time capnography) or as a function of expired
volume  (volumetric  capnography).  The  recording  produced  by  a  capnography  monitoring
device is a waveform known as capnogram which reveals information about the underlying
cardiopulmonary condition of the patient.&lt;br&gt;
Quantitative  analysis  of  the  capnogram  would  allow  capnography  to  be  used  as  a
monitoring  and  diagnostic  tool.  In  this  thesis,  this  type  of  analysis  was  performed  by
decomposing  the  volumetric  capnogram  into  physiological  features.  Feature  extraction
methods was performed and a machine learning algorithm was applied (decision trees) to distinguish between healthy and diseased patients. Moreover, methods for
assessing the classifier performance of decision trees are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
